{
    "id": "da2cdd37aad742efb0b03bc9cf21c157",
    "title": "Adverbs and Adjectives Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The evening was …………………. cold.",
            "description": "Bitter is an adjective and bitterly is an adverb. We use adverbs to modify verbs and adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "bitter",
                "bitterly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a379bff9309842c8899b8c4f1ab1a5b6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I couldn’t help ………………….. at the joke.",
            "description": "The expression 'couldn’t help + ing' has the same meaning as the expression 'couldn’t help but + infinitive without to'.",
            "answers": [
                "but laugh",
                "laughing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9a15ad3b2b7e4e40a24ea5c19381b5f3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have never seen a more …………………. cricket match.",
            "description": "A match cannot be excited. An exciting match keeps spectators excited. ",
            "answers": [
                "exciting",
                "excited",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6ffdce9f3b484dda964ca16b988d68a3"
        },
        {
            "question": "This movie is ……………….. interesting.",
            "description": "Very and so are possible here. Too has a negative meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "too",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2589b362049544eebfca5bb6f66136bd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ……………… annoyed to hear this.",
            "description": "Very and so are not followed by to-infinitives.",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "so",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f4ea7cc0ec7b48b78c233ae6c54fbbf4"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was ………………. tired that he could barely stand.",
            "description": "Note the pattern: so…that…",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "too",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3fbfffecafb04704b212f59ee9763f19"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must not waste your ………………. earned money.",
            "description": "The correct expression is 'hard-earned money'. Hardly is similar to scarcely. ",
            "answers": [
                "hard",
                "hardly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e99eecdeb99b4fea8fa45e546b026a00"
        },
        {
            "question": "No one can write as ……………….. as he does.",
            "description": "Neat is an adjective and neatly is an adverb. We need an adverb to modify a verb.",
            "answers": [
                "neat",
                "neatly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "065f0efbd9fc47498f88cf086f8bc430"
        },
        {
            "question": "I cannot by ……………… means allow you to go.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "no",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "81bc8a45fc5c49f88015c1c124000714"
        },
        {
            "question": "The fish tasted …………………",
            "description": "Taste is a copular verb. After copular verbs we use adjectives, not adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "awful",
                "awfully",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4ccf4485eae6443aa1bf6956ba2043f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "The problem looked ………………….",
            "description": "Look is a copular verb. After copular verbs, we use adjectives, not adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "difficult",
                "difficultly",
                "difficulty"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "16329e212c0a4bed86df5fab4c43504d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………. having read a more enjoyable book.",
            "description": "The use of never for not is incorrect in many cases. ",
            "answers": [
                "never remember",
                "do not remember",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f1bcbd1bfe904b8c8b9bc8b175762077"
        }
    ]
}